# MD SHAH NEWAZ SARKER

IT & HR Professional



LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/md-shah-newazsarker-842b9535;

#### GitHub:

- https://github.com/UniversityOfAppliedScien cesFrankfurt/se-cloud-2020-2021.git;
- https://gitlab.unikoblenz.de/lieferantentool/lieferantentool\_fro ntend/-/tree/Frontend\_development\_angular\_ Sarker?ref\_type=heads

mdshahnewazsarker5@gmail.com sumon20007@yahoo.com Saurborn Str. 14, 56073 Koblenz +49-015781422485

□ Please Click To Check My Portfolio

## About Me

I am a diligent IT and HR professional with years of experience in manufacturing, recruiting, education, service provider, and construction & maintenance organizations with HR, IT, and Logistics applications.

I am skilled in developing plans, providing support for IT systems, managing HR functions, and personnel record management.

## **Work Experience**

## **Research Assistant**

UNIVERSITY OF KOBLENZ, a well-known public university in Koblenz, Germany

September 2023 to December 2024 (1 year, 3 months)

- Assist in the Literature review, Data collection, and documentation to the professor relevant to enterprise architecture concepts, methodologies, and best practices.
- Contribute to the creation of course materials, Collaborate with instructors, professors, and other research assistants to exchange ideas, Perform administrative tasks, assignments, and final paper assessment & grading.
- Assis in Process modeling for the PEPPOL(Pen-Europian Public Procurement Online) project and Contributes as a Front-end developer for the delivery tool of PEPPOL using HTML/CSS and Angular.



## IT, HR, and Admin Manager

ZEIL WEARS LIMITED, a 100% export-oriented footwear manufacturing group of companies in Chittagong, Bangladesh

January 2018 to October 2020 (2 years, 9 months)

- Managing and maintaining the company's IT infrastructure, including servers, networks, and workstations, and ensuring the smooth operation, security, and availability of systems, providing user support to end-users
- Responsible for key HR functionalities (Recruitment and Selection, HR Policies and Procedures development, Compensation and Benefits, Training and Development, Employee Onboarding and Offboarding, Performance Management, and Compliance.)
- Lead the factory HR, admin, and compliance team by ensuring the team is fully aware of their role and expectations.
- Assist Plant head and CEO in preparing yearly manpower forecasting and organizational resource management planning.



## IT, Field Administrator, and Deputy HR Manager

BONATTI. OIL & GAS INTEGRAL SOLUTIONS PROVIDER, an international general contractor providing services to the energy industry, has projects in 13 countries around the world (Parma, Italy).

May 2009 to June 2017 (8 years, 1 month)

## As Field Administrator:

- Daily and monthly Timekeeping, and reporting to the branch office (Tripoli, Libya) and head office (Parma, Italy) for individual employees (locals and expatriates) present on site of different construction and maintenance projects.
- Handling and reporting the project's accounts to the branch office accurately.
- Successfully managed personnel database, documentation, residence permit, and salary-related issues in collaboration with local authorities and the branch office(Labour office, Emigration office, etc.)
- Perform all administrative activities related to several projects' Camp management alliance with local subcontractor.
- Triumphantly performed several projects' asset(heavy and light vehicle and equipment) management.

# Work Experience

## As IT Administrator:

- Updating and monitoring IT user accounts, IT security effectively by IT risk assessment framework NST 800-300.
- Maintenance and management of the Windows-based server environment in several projects.
- Able to provide maintenance support and break-fix solutions.
- Managing and monitoring system backups in multi-project site locations for emergency evacuation.
- Liaising & meeting with an external ISP [Libya Telecom & Technology (LTT)] & local computer hardware companies, as suppliers of IT services.
- Troubleshooting technical problems and implementing solutions.

## As Deputy HR Manager:

- Accurately and efficiently perform all HR functions (Recruiting, hiring, sourcing, employee engagement, performance management, etc. in collaboration with department supervisors)
- HR forecasting, vacation scheduling, performance appraisal, auditing timekeeping reports, managing travel tickets, and resolving issues related to emigration.
- Supervising field administrator for all administrative tasks; project manhour reporting to project director and client (Mellitah oil and gas, Libya); incident investigation, reporting, and taking disciplinary actions accordingly.
- Arranging employee training, safety drills, and emergency evacuation events.



#### **Admin Executive**

BLUESTAR SERVICES, a renowned overseas recruiting, and human development agency in Dhaka, Bangladesh July 2008 to April 2009 (9 months)

- Administrative & employee records documentation and mail correspondence with overseas clients.
- Performs planning, recruiting & selection, and training functions for various overseas projects through employee management software.
- Conducts Computer Hardware, employee management software, domain server, and LAN troubleshooting.
- Handling visa issues of each project's employees and hosting Foreign recruiters.



## **Computer Instructor**

CANTONMENT ENGLISH SCHOOL, an English medium school in Chittagong, Bangladesh

March 2008 to June 2008 (3 months)

- Maintain the LAN of the Computer Lab of 50 computers; Storing all the student records in Student Database Software
- Facilitate training for all the teachers about Microsoft Office and Oracle 8i and maintain all the gadgets for computing teaching.



## **Programmer**

COPOTRONIC INFO SYSTEMS LTD, a growing software farm in Chittagong, Bangladesh)

June 2007 to February 2008 (9 months)

- Gain client satisfaction by successful installation and providing training on the timekeeping, payroll, inventory, and accounting software at the client end.
- Develop and customize software according to the Client accord and alliance(like Inventory, Hotel Management, Time Tracker, and Payroll) using Oracle Developer 6i and Oracle 8i.



## Relevant IT and HR Skills

- Employee Recruitment, Onboarding/Orientation, Performance appraisal, training, and development.
- Employee relations, Analytical skills.
- Communication skills, Customer Orientation, and leadership.
- Timekeeping and personnel management.
- · Sourcing and interviewing.
- · Critical Problem Solving.
- Conceptual modeling and experience in agile methodology.
- · Team Building.
- IT hardware and software installation and troubleshooting.
- .Net, MS Sharepoint, Outlook, SQL, Microsoft Office, Microsoft Windows, User Support, Oracle 6i & 8i, Visio, Visual Studio CodeAdobe, HTML/CSS, Angular, Photoshop, Mendeley, ARIS Express, ADONIS, GitHub, Signavio, Modelio, Network Administration, Transcoll(Time Attendance software in MSDOS), COBRA (Logistic software in MSDOS), Automated Time Attendance, and Payroll software associated with fingerprint and proximity card.

# **Education History**



#### **Master in E-Government**

Institution: Universität Koblenz-Landau

Year of Graduation: Continuing



## Masters of Business Administration(Executive) major in HRM

Institution: University of Science and Technology Chittagong (USTC)

Year of Graduation: 2020 (German Grade: 1.38)

 Research Project on "Measurement of Cost of Employee Absenteeism, Turnover & Retention of Zeil Wears Limited"



## Post Graduate Diploma in Human Resource and Management

Institution: Bangladesh Institute of Management (BIM), Chittagong, Bangladesh.

Year of Graduation: 2018 German Grade: 1.17)

• Term Paper and TP presentation on "Employee Absenteeism, Turnover & Retention: A Study on Midas Safety Bangladesh"



## **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering**

Institution: University of Science and Technology Chittagong (USTC)

Year of Graduation: 2007 (German Grade: 2.50)

• Group project on an automation solution of "Seals & Purchasing process of Royal Cement".



## Certification and License

- Cisco Certified Network Associate Routing and Switching (CCNA) from Chittagong University of Engineering and Technology
- Driving license Federal Republic of Germany (AM/B/L); Verfallsdatum: 21.10.2036



Bangla(Native), English(7.0), German(B1), Hindi(Fluent).



## Volunteer Work and Affiliations

## **Field Engineer**

Institution: Canopus IT Solutions, Crestech IT

#### 2022 to Present

- Travel to the client's (Q-Park, Baker & Baker Netherlands Holding B.V., ElringKlinger AG) locations or various sites (Bonn, Koeln, Remagan) to provide hands-on IT support according to service requests, troubleshoot hardware and software issues, and resolve IT problems promptly and efficiently concerning the Cradlepoint IBR600c router installation.
- Perform on-request maintenance and repairs on computer systems, laptops, printers, scanners, and other hardware peripherals. Moreover, diagnose hardware failures, replace faulty components, and perform upgrades as necessary.

## **Buddy**

Institution: Universität Koblenz-Landau 2023 to Present

Facilitate newcomers with onboarding in the University.

# Seminar paper contribution (Universität Koblenz-Landau):

- Smart City Development of Hamburg, Palo Alto, Amsterdam and Oslo, focus on Smart Governance.
- Digitalization of 'Ring LLC' from Baseline to Target architecture.
- A Comparative Analysis of eHealth Services in Two European Public Governance Systems: Belgium and Denmark ,Focus on eHealth and Public Governance

## Project Experiences:

• IT and Field Administrator (2009-2011)

Project: Logistic Brega (Brega, Libya)
Org: BONATTI. OIL & GAS INTEGRAL
SOLUTIONS PROVIDER

• IT and Field Administrator (2011-2013)

Project: Nafoora, Bu-Attifel, Wafa (Libya) Org: BONATTI. OIL & GAS INTEGRAL SOLUTIONS PROVIDER

• IT and Deputy HR Manager (2013-2017)

Project: Mellitah area: Complex and Gas Compressor Station (Libya) Org: BONATTI. OIL & GAS INTEGRAL SOLUTIONS PROVIDER